# IHE MPD (Medication Prescription and Dispense) Profile

The IHE MPD profile sets a universal baseline amidst varying regulations and practices in medication management across jurisdictions. Focused on interoperability, it identifies commonalities and standardizes pivotal data points to facilitate seamless integration across diverse healthcare systems.

## Overview

The MPD Profile emphasizes a unified set of guidelines, ensuring that while medication prescription and dispensing processes may differ by jurisdiction or drug type, fundamental data and processes remain interoperable.

## Key Features

1. **Unified Medication Ordering**: Harmonizing varied prescription scenarios, order grouping, and validation workflows to ensure consistency across jurisdictions.
2. **Standardized Medication Dispensing**: Addressing cross-jurisdictional challenges, special preparations, and varying contexts of hospital and community dispensing.
3. **Comprehensive Medication Data**: Establishing standardized data sets and terminologies to represent medication data universally.

## Organization of This Guide 

### Volume 1: Use Cases and Standards

This section delves into functional aspects, detailing various use cases, and standardizing them for a global perspective.

- **Prescriptions**: Types and content of prescriptions.
- **Order Grouping**: Grouping of orders with and without interdependencies.
- **Ordering Workflows**: Common workflow aspects for medication ordering, considering approval, review, etc. with allowances for jurisdiction-specific requirements.

### Volume 2: Transactions

This technical section focuses on the technical data exchange.

- **Prescription Placement**:
- **Prescription Consult**
- **Dispense Report**: 

### Volume 3: Content and Terminology

The medicinal product data structure and terminology ensures the correct identification and description of the products.

- **Medication Resource Definition**: A common data structure to represent any medication.
- **Terminologies**: Common terminologies for he product and its attributes.

### Other Resources:

- **Download and Analysis**: [Link](download_mpd.html)

For a detailed view, refer to the [Table of Contents](toc_mpd.html) or the index of [Artifacts](artifacts.html).

## Must Support

Within the MPD profile, `Must Support` elements signify core elements that must be commonly understood and not ignored.

---

